<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<beer>
  <id>Tyanena-Brewing-Company/Fargo-Brothers-Hefeweizen</id>
  <brewery_id>Tyanena-Brewing-Company</brewery_id>
  <ibu>12</ibu>
  <name>Fargo Brothers Hefeweizen</name>
  <description>The Fargo brothers arrived in Lake Mills in 1845, armed with a strong collective will and a pioneering spirit. The Fargo family became leaders in commerce, industry, agriculture, civics and religion. Through the years, these hard working men and their families shaped the character and very essence of our beautiful hometown. Their legacy endures in the buildings and businesses they built and the civility they brought to this city. In this same pioneering spirit, we brew our Fargo Brothers Hefeweizen to honor this "first family" of Lake Mills.Enoch and Lyman opened the Fargo drygoods store in 1845. In 1851, Enoch purchased the mills which helped provide Lake Mills with its name. In 1868, Enoch and Lyman organized the first foundry east of Milwaukee.Ê Enoch also maintained interests in a grocery store, a farm and dairy, and the Lake View Hotel.Robert worked for his brothers in the store before becoming a telegrapher. Lorenzo homesteaded 500 acres and had 500 sheep was was a renowned philanthropist.Ê Isaac served a pastor of the newly organized Baptist Church.Ê Joseph built the city's first jail.\nThe Lake Mills Fargo family legacy is remembered to this day in the L.D. Fargo Library (donated by Lorenzo D. Fargo), the Fargo Mansion Bed and Breakfast (home of Enoch's son), Crepaco (founded by Enoch's sons and one of Lake Mills largest employers), the Bank of Lake Mills (founded in part by the Fargo family), the Fargo Mercantile, Fargo Street, and the city's electric company (founded by Enoch's sons).Fargo Brothers Hefeweizen is brewed in the tradition of a Bavarian-style wei§bier with a clove-like flavor and aroma with banana undertones and no bitterness.Ê The unfiltered yeast makes this beer cloudy.</description>
  <availability>limited</availability>
  <ingredients/>
  <grains>2-row, Wheat</grains>
  <grains>2-row, Wheat</grains>
  <hops>perle,saaz</hops>
  <yeast/>
  <otherings/>
  <styles>
    <style><name>hefeweizen </name></style>
  </styles>
</beer>
