<?xml version="1.0"?>
<beer id="Dieu-Du-Ciel/Saison-St-louis" brewery_id="Dieu-Du-Ciel" abv="6">
  <name>SAISON ST-LOUIS</name>
  <description>The brewing of the Saison St-Louis is inspired by the beers that are brewed in the south-west of Belgium. The term &#xD2;Saison&#xD3; refers to a family of beers rather than a precise style. In the old days, this beer was brewed on farms where there was a brewery that served the needs of the workers and the owners. These breweries produced the Saison during the winter months so that they could drink the beer in the summer, when it was too hot to brew. To preserve the beer over several months, the beers had to be stronger in alcohol content and/or more hops were added than in other beers. The artisan or small scale production of these beers made it so that the recipes varied wildly from one brewery to another. The grain used depended on the cereals available at the farm when the beer was being brewed: barley, wheat, rye, buckwheat, or spelt. The malt drying procedures, being more archaic at the time, made for beers that were much darker than they are today. Today, these beers tend to be blond. The use of spices was left to the whim of the brewer, but they were always used in moderation, and never to override the other flavours in the beer. It used to be a top fermenting beer, where the starter culture was mixed with different strains of yeast and lactate producing bacteria. With the evolution of brewing methods and knowledge in microbiological techniques, the lactic character of the beer disappeared over time. The Saison St-Louis is a contemporary version of the style. It is brewed with pale barley malt and a portion of raw wheat. The hoppiness of the beer comes from the use of English hops. Flavoured with coriander, it is a blond beer, very mildly acidic, of medium bitterness, full-bodied without being sweet, and has cookie and citrus flavours. This is the perfect thirst quencher after a hard day&#xD5;s labour on the farm!</description>
  <availability/>
  <ingredients/>
  <grains/>
  <grains/>
  <hops/>
  <yeast/>
  <otherings/>
  <styles>
    <style>saison</style>
  </styles>
</beer>
